He's not a killer, but he can pretend.
Hit Man is a comedy, romance, crime film directed by Richard Linklater.
A mild-mannered professor moonlighting as a fake hit man in police stings ignites
a chain reaction of trouble when he falls for a potential client.
Gary Johnson, played by Glen Powell.
Madison Figueroa Masters, played by Adria Arjona.
Jasper, played by Austin Amelio.
Claudette, played by Retta.
Phil, played by Sanjay Rao.
Alicia, played by Molly Bernard.
Hit Man is a 2023 American romantic crime comedy film produced and directed by
Richard Linklater, who co-wrote the screenplay with Glen Powell.
The film stars Powell, Adria Arjona, Austin Amelio, Retta, and Sanjay Rao.
It follows an undercover New Orleans police contractor who poses as a
reliable hitman as he tries to save a woman in need.
The basic premise was based on the true story of a college professor who worked for the Houston police in the late
1980s and 1990s as a fake hitman, as described in a 2001 magazine article by Skip Hollandsworth.
Hit Man premiered at the 80th Venice International
Film Festival on September 5, 2023.
It was released in select theaters in the United States on May 24, 2024, before
its streaming debut by Netflix on June 7, to critical acclaim.
The film explores themes of hitman, identity,
professor, new orleans, louisiana, romcom.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.